# Dillon Streator

# Full-Stack Developer

# **PROFILE**

I am a passionate Full Stack Developer who has been recently focused on Node, Express, and Angular 2+. Additionally, I possess a mindset for high drive, continuous improvement, and dedication to quality work. I am excited to work for an organization that instills best coding practices across the team and motivates and encourages inquisitive minds.

#### **PROJECTS**

# Boilerplate admin panel

Created a boilerplate administrative dashboard for quickly spinning up an API server with JWT authentication and middleware for JWT authorization. Additionally, I created a basic administrative interface with multiple permission levels allowing for viewing of frontend activity and logs (Access, Email, and Error logs), and user management.

 NPM dependencies: express, ejs, express-session, passport, jsonwebtoken, mongodb, mongoose, moment, bcrypt, device

#### Apartments.rank

Built an apartment ranking application that displays curated apartment listings based on user input criteria including walkability, crime rate threshold, car availability, and work commute times

- Utilized the inverse Pythagorean theorem to develop geo-location algorithm to visually display spatial crime statics for Chicago residential neighborhoods.
- Developed proprietary algorithm which optimizes apartment characteristics tailored to user input criteria.
- Front-end: Materialize, JavaScript, AJAX
- Backend: Rails, City of Chicago APIs, Google (maps) Developer Suite/Cloud Platform, Unirest

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Director of Development**

Youtech & Associates | Naperville, IL | 6/2018 - Present

- Manage a team of 7 developers both local and remote
- · First to assume Director position within department
- Sole architect behind:
  - Workflow structure; including git, code reviews, and testing
  - · Creating and conducting meetings on both a team and personal level
  - Personal & professional development of team through sponsored events and lightning talks
- Maintain and grow new and existing client relationships via quick and effective communication and providing detailed explanation of expectations.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Youtech & Associates | Naperville, IL | 9/2017 - 6/2018

- Responsible for independently planning, prioritizing, and executing development of complex custom web and mobile applications.
- Interface and communicate with external and internal clients from design to marketing to C-suite management to end-users on project needs and status.
- Assist web designers with WordPress and Magento third party plugin/extension installation conflict resolution
- Create custom WordPress and Magento plugin/extensions
- Tech utilized: Node, Express, Mongodb, Mongoose, MYSQL, MSSQL, Magento, WordPress, Shopify

#### **SKILLS**

# **Core Programming**

- Node
- Ruby
- OOP, Functional, and Reactive programming
- RESTful APIs
- Microservices
- TDD
- OAuth2.0
- JWT

#### Frameworks/Libraries

- Express
- Rails
- Angular 2+
- React
- Vue
- Nativescript (cross-platform native app development framework)
- Bootstrap
- Materialize
- iQuery
- Socket.io
- Passport
- RxJS

# **Workflow Tools**

- Git
- Github & Gitlab
- Ngrok
- CI
- Agile
- Slack
- Trello
- TeamWork

#### **Databases**

- MYSQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Mongodb
- Relational database design

# **EDUCATION**

Actualize | 2017

Full-Stack Development

Harper College | 2014

A.A.S. in Electronics Engineering Technologies

# CONTACT

Chicago, IL dillonstreator@gmail.com 224-619-7327

**github**.com/DillonStreator **linkedin**.com/in/dillon-streator-75b01b83/

# Full-Stack Web Developer

Difference Engine | Chicago, IL | 5/2017 - 8/2017

Worked as a lead developer to provide a full stack e-commerce solution for a non-profit coffee subscription company.

- Responsible for developing admin workspace, fully responsive integrated shopping cart, and database architecture
- Frontend: JavaScript, React, CSS, HTML 5, AJAX
- Backend: Microservices, RESTful API, Rails, and various libraries (Stripe, Devise, SendGrid, RSPEC)
- Teamwork productivity tools: GitHub, Slack, Trello, Pair Programming, SCRUM, TDD

#### **Technical Service Engineer**

Keyence Corporation | Itasca, IL | 2015 - 2017

- Review and understand technical documentation on 20+ product lines ranging from safety sensors, high precision measurement sensors, machine vision systems, and digital microscopes.
- Provide technical troubleshooting of customer equipment and applications regarding aforementioned product lines.
- Detail oriented analysis of hardware at the component level, utilizing device schematics.